ASIF NAWAZ

Street #111, Sector I-8/4, Islamabad

+92 340 7891017 URDU

asifnawaz.miani@gmail.com ENGLISH

LinkedIn: <u>asifnawazmiani</u> PUNJABI

> Summary:

A .NET technologies professional with 4+ years of experience and expertise in 3rd-party API integrations and a successful track record of delivering multiple web and desktop projects currently in production. Committed to teamwork and continuous learning and growth through new challenges and responsibilities.

Technical Skills:

- Core Skills: C#, ASP.NET MVC, Web APIs, Windows Services, MS SQL Server, 3rd party integrations, TFVC, GIT.
- Programming Languages: C#, Visual Basic .NET and JavaScript.
- Frameworks and Libraries: ASP .NET MVC, Web APIs, Web Forms, Win Forms, Windows Services, WPF, Angular 15.x (TS), VUE JS, Blazor (.NET Core), HTML, CSS, SCSS, JQuery, .NET Framework, .NET Core.
- Database technologies: MS SQL Server.
- Architectural Styles: N-Tier Architecture, Facade, Factory Method Pattern, OOP.
- Data Access Technologies: ADO .NET, Dapper, LINQ to SQL.
- Reporting: Crystal Reports, RDLC, Fast Reports.
- Integrations: Proficient in integrating 3rd-party APIs, including KYC services such as Identity Mind, KYC Hub and Acuant, as well as BulkSMS, Cdyne, and Fintech integrations like Transact365, Machnet, Transfast, Access Bank etc.
- Version Control and DevOps: Azure DevOps, GIT, Team Foundation Version Control.
- Methodologies: Agile/Scrum methodologies, Project management system (PMS), Azure DevOps Boards.

Soft Skills:

- Effective communication and collaboration skills; able work effectively with colleagues and clients.
- Detail-oriented and precise in work and dependable and reliable in meeting deadlines.
- Capable of adjusting to dynamic work environments with changing priorities and timelines.
- Strong problem-solving and critical thinking skills, and motivated to take initiative on my own.
- Enjoy actively seeking out opportunities to learn and improve my technical skills through self-directed study and research.

> Experiences:

White Wings Consulting (Islamabad)

Software Engineer II (May 2022 - To Date) Software Engineer I (Apr 2021 - May 2022)

- Skills: ASP .NET MVC, WEB API, MS SQL Server, Web Forms, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Responsibilities: To enhance existing systems and add new features to system and dealing directly with clients.
- Accomplishments: Delivered projects for 5+ clients with daily transactions of 2K-5K, meeting deadlines and ensuring timely delivery.
 Introduced CMS pattern and same codebase to configure new clients, reducing development time and resource efforts by 40%.

BroadPeak Technologies (Islamabad)

Software Engineer I (Nov 2021 - Apr 2020)

- Skills: WPF, Desktop Win Forms, WEB APIs, Web Forms, MS SQL Server.
- Responsibilities: Refactoring and modifying legacy code base.
- Accomplishments: By refactoring code base, the system performance improved up to 20%.

ESSCom Solutions Pvt. Ltd (Islamabad)

Associate Software Engineer (Jul 2019 - Nov 2020) Junior Software Engineer (Jul 2018 - Jul 2019)

- Skills: Win Forms, Web Forms, ASP .NET MVC, WEB APIs, MS SQL Server, TFS Server.
- Responsibilities: Interacting clients, product ownership, maintain and add-on to systems.
- Accomplishments: By completing 10-12 satisfied clients that generated 30% of revenue, while consistently pushing project boundaries to deliver exceptional results.

Honors & awards:

- Honored with the Employee of the Month award at White Wings Consulting for exceptional performance and contributions to the team.
- Received recognition for creative problem-solving skills by White Wings Consulting at the 2022 annual event.

Ongoing Learning:

- Expect to complete the Angular training program in 3 months, allowing me to start working on Angular projects immediately and contributing to the company's development pipeline.
- Excited to apply my new skills in Angular app development and deployment processes, as well as Azure DevOps CI/CD, to help enhance almost 90% of quality and delivery of our software products.

Educational:

- Master in Computer Science, Virtual University of Pakistan (2018-23)
 - Completed degree program after overcoming academic challenges.
- Bachelors in Computer Science, Punjab University Lahore Pakistan (Affiliated College) (2016-18)

Projects:

- OTM (Online Transaction System) White Wings Consulting:
 - Tech Stack: ASP .NET MVC, Web APIs, MS SQL Server, JQuery, API Integrations.
 - Designed and implemented features such as KYC, SMS and email service integrations, coupon system, and intelligent system for selecting merchants based on transaction data.
 - Contributed to the development of a web portal for customers to create online transactions.

MTS (Money Transfer System) - White Wings Consulting:

- Tech Stack: C#, VB .NET, ASP .NET Web Forms, MS SQL Server, JQuery, Windows Services.
- Developed reports, coupon system, 3rd party payment processor integrations, and KYC systems.
- Worked on integrations with banks and e-wallets to facilitate international money transfers.

■ SMS-Store Management System - BroadPeak Technologies:

• Served in the factorization process of code for an international POS solution used by edible stores.

■ Biometric Attendance Management System - ESSCom Solutions:

- Tech Stack: C#, ASP .NET Web Forms, MS SQL Server, JQuery, Windows Services, Win Forms.
- Developed an attendance system used by organizations such as SCP, Fauji Foundation, and ECP.
- Single-handedly built the app, which included features such as real-time attendance tracking and reporting.

Queue Management System - ESSCom Solutions:

- Tech Stack: C#, Win Forms, Web APIs, MS SQL Server, Embedded systems i.e. Arduino.
- Configured for domestic and foreign clients.
- Single-handedly built the app, which included features such as queue management and real-time reporting.

Enterprise Management System - ESSCom Solutions:

Assisted seniors to develop a mini ERP software for factory management.

Access Control Management System ESSCom Solutions:

- Gave support in enhancement of features for an access control system through RFID cards installed in Shifa International Hospital.
- **Joppler:** Online job portal made in AngularJS aka Angular 1.x.